## AVALINE AI

San Diego, CA 91942 | Tel: 858-735-3908 | Email: avaline.ai@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/Avalineai

Portfolio: https://avalineai.github.io/9-Portfolio/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/avaline-ai-b94b89178/

#### SUMMARY

Front end developer who solves programming challenges in a team environment and delivers streamlined, meaningful client-user experiences. Open-minded, teachable, and optimistic collaborator, with years of experience in intercommunication and problem solving through retail and clerical work. Brings a passion for learning quickly and working with new technology while simultaneously helping customers and companies alike in fulfilling their goals and needs.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Node.js

Windows 10, 7, Server, Vista, and XP, Apple OS Operating Systems:

Version Control Systems: Git

Others: Microsoft Office Suite (including Visio and Project), MySQL

Cloud: **AWS** 

#### **P**ROJECTS

My Closet - Link to Github <a href="https://github.com/Avalineai/project">https://github.com/Avalineai/project</a> 2 **Fullstack Developer** 

Link to Deployed Project https://project2uscd.herokuapp.com/

- Core responsibilities included creating mySQL database
- Creating user input forms and pages
- Testing user input and serving content from database
- Tools: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Handlebars, Javascript, Materialize, Sequelize

The Rabbit Hole - Link to Github https://github.com/thejihongjin/8-Project-1

**Frontend Developer** 

Link to Deployed Project https://thejihongjin.github.io/8-Project-1/

- Utilizing multiple APIs focused on bringing fun, humor, and stress relief to the user experience
- Core responsibilities included researching results of API data structure and CSS styling
- Tools: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Javascript, Bootstrap

Word Guess Game - Link to Github https://github.com/Avalineai/WordGuessGame Sole Developer Link to Deployed Project https://avalineai.github.io/WordGuessGame/

- Themed hangman-style game which takes user input to match against array of strings, and outputs scores and results based on user interaction
- Researched and constructed simple game
- Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap

GifTastic - Link to Github https://github.com/Avalineai/GifTastic

Frontend Developer

Link to Deployed Project https://avalineai.github.io/GifTastic/

- Using Giphy API, the project generates themed gifs and also accepts user input to generate more gifs
- Researched and constructed project
- Tools: HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap

#### EXPERIENCE

Account Executive 2019-current
Accredited Debt Relief San Diego, CA

• Communicate effectively in a fast paced environment by using industry specific knowledge and demonstrating that expertise by assisting clients regarding their financial needs.

# Member Services Representative San Diego Association of Realtors

2018-2019 San Diego, CA

- Promoted to manage stand-alone Service Center Office Location within first 6 months in the role.
- Learned and implemented industry specific proprietary software and hardware in less than one week.
- Provided efficient and accurate customer service: communicated effectively, troubleshooted technical and account issues, and evaluated possible solutions.

### Proposals Department Manager

2016-2018

Consumer's Alliance Processing Corporation

Carlsbad, CA

#### **EDUCATION**

The Coding Bootcamp-Full Stack Flex Program: University of California San Diego Extension
San Diego, CA
2019-current

Business Administration (undergraduate courses online): Southern New Hampshire University, Manchester, NH 2014-2016